viagogo.com 2019-12-25

# viagogo - Buy & Sell Concert, Sport & Theatre Tickets

## Privacy Policy

**_About us_**

**_What information do we collect?_**

**_How do we use your information?_**

**_Who do we share your information with?_**

**_Ensuring that use of your information is lawful_**

**_Where do we send your information?_**

**_How long do we keep your information?_**

**_Making a complaint_**

**_Your Privacy rights_**

**_About us_**

viagogo respects your privacy and protecting your information is paramount. We want you to be informed and empowered with respect to your privacy when you use our services. Please read this Privacy Notice carefully before using our website or apps or registering to use our services. Together with our Terms and Conditions and the Cookies Policy, this Privacy Notice sets out our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we use, process and treat the personal data you provide to us or we collect about you and the rights you have in relation to the protection of your personal data. 

The data controller of your personal data is viagogo AG of Rue Du Commerce 4, 1204 Geneva, Switzerland.  We use your information as further explained in this Privacy Notice.  We do so jointly with viagogo Entertainment Inc of 160 Greentree Drive, Suite 101, Dover, Delaware, County of Kent, 19904, USA. If you do make a request to us in respect of your personal information (see the ‘Your Privacy rights’ section below for more information), viagogo AG will lead in responding to your request and viagogo Entertainment Inc will assist fully where required.

The representative in the European Union (EU) for both viagogo AG and viagogo Entertainment Inc is VGL Support Services Ireland Limited, and for further information about our use of your personal data, or your rights under data protection law, please contact [privacyrequest@orders.viagogo.com](mailto:privacyrequest@orders.viagogo.com). Note: we won't respond to emails sent to this email address that are not related to your privacy rights. For other enquiries, please contact customer services  here .

**_What information do we collect?_**

We may collect and process the following data about you:

**Information you give us.** You may give us information about you when you register with our website or our apps or by communicating with us by phone, email, social media or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you create a customer account, use our services, provide us with identification information required to verify your identity or in connection with the issue of your tickets, provide us with feedback, participate in surveys, and when you report a problem with our website. The information you give us may include your name, address, email address, phone number, date of birth, copies of formal identity documents such as your passport of ID card and credit or debit card details.

**Information we collect about you based on your use of our website or apps.** Each time you visit our website or use our app we may automatically collect the following information:

**(a)**       **Technical information** , including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your device to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, operating system, device information (such as the model and version of your device), platform and;

**(b)**        **Information about your visit** , including products and events you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page and any data entered into the page during your visit; and

**(c)**       **Location Data** , including your precise location (longitude and latitude details with the time that the details are captured), which is provided by using information, such as your IP address or GPS sensors.  We will only collect information about your location if you have provided consent for us to do so.

**Information we receive from other sources.** We work closely with third parties including, for example, our fraud prevention providers and email address / telephone number verification service providers. We may receive information about you from these third parties to verify information you provide to us which helps us to identify suspicious or unusual transactions.

**Information collected from cookies.   **We and our service providers collect information about your use of our website using cookies. For information about our use of cookies and how to decline them or turn them off please read our **Cookies Policy**.

**Recording telephone calls and other communications.**   We may monitor or record telephone conversations or other communications between you and us. 

We use the information described above for the purposes set out in the **How do we use your information?** section below.   

**_How do we use your information?_**

**Information you give to us or we collect from third parties on your behalf as part of our services**

We will only use this information to:

(a)       Enable you to purchase tickets through our website, administer your account, manage your relationship with us, and to communicate with you by telephone, mail, email, text (SMS) message, instant messaging or other electronic means;

(b)      verify your identity as part of our identity authentication process and to prevent, detect and prosecute fraud and crime and to comply with our legal or regulatory requirements;

(c)      provide evidence of your identity to sellers in connection with the issue of tickets; notify you about changes to our services;

(d)      ensure that content from our website is presented in the most effective manner for you   and your device;

(e)      aggregate your information on an anonymous basis with other data for data analytical and reporting purposes;

(f)      undertake analysis and profiling of your browsing history and purchases (and any other data provided by you or on your behalf or which we collect on your behalf) in order to identify and inform you of products and services that we consider are likely to interest you;

(g)      in combination with information we collect about you based on your use of our website, undertake testing and analysis of new products, services and website / app functionality to help us to assess the impact of these new features and improve the service we offer you; and

(g)      where you have provided your consent to receive marketing material from us, provide you with information about other products and services that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about or about products or services that may be of interest to you. 

**Information we collect about you based on your use of our website**

We will use this information:

(a)      to administer our website and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;

(b)      to build up a picture of your interests so that you don’t miss information relevant to you when you visit our website;

(c)      to improve the service we offer you and to try and ensure that you get the best from our website, ensuring that content is tailored and presented in the most effective manner for you and for the devices you use to access it;

(d)      as part of our efforts to keep our website safe and secure;

(e)      to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you; and

(f)      to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our website about products or services that may interest you or them.

We also use the device information and battery charging information we collect from you to improve the performance of our apps and to refine the user experience while using our website and apps.  For example, we use the device information to check whether any updates we are making will work on your tablet or phone, and to check how our apps are affecting your battery life.

**Information we receive from other sources**

We combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may use this information and the combined information for identity verification and fraud detection, prevention and prosecution purposes as set out above.

**Recording telephone calls and other communications**

We will use telephone recordings or transcripts of communications to check your instructions to us, analyse, assess and improve our services to customers, for training and quality purposes and for the purposes of investigating any complaint you may make, or as evidence in any dispute or anticipated disputes between you and us.

**We also use technology to make decisions automatically about you**

We employ technology which uses logic to analyse transactions you enter into against the information we collect from you or from third parties about you. This helps us to identify unusual or suspicious transactions in order to detect and prevent fraud. What this means for you is that where an attempted transaction appears to be suspicious, unusual or otherwise out of the ordinary, we may automatically decline to proceed with the transaction.

You’ve the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which has legal consequences for you or similarly significant effects. While we’re confident that the technology works, if you have any questions about our automated decision making process, you can contact us via [privacyrequest@orders.viagogo.com](mailto:privacyrequest@orders.viagogo.com).

**_Marketing_**

We offer you the opportunity to receive marketing information from us. We will normally send direct marketing by email if we have your email address, but may choose to contact you via other methods, if you have provided your consent for us to market to you using these methods.

If you consented to receive marketing communications when you registered and created a customer account, you can tell us that you do not wish to receive any more at any time by selecting the ‘unsubscribe’ option in the marketing communications we send or at any time by changing your account preferences.

**_Who do we share your information with?_**

In addition to sharing your information with other members of our group (including our subsidiaries and affiliated companies), we may need to disclose your data to third parties in order to ensure that we can provide you with our services and to ensure effective operation of our website and the apps.

We may share your information with the following third parties:

(a)         other users and ticket sellers in order to enable them to verify your identity and/or provide you with tickets you have bought through our website or app (e.g. for the purposes of posting your tickets to you);

(b)         business partners, third party suppliers and our subcontractors (including delivery companies, payment providers and fraud prevention providers) to enable us to provide our services, operate our websites and app and to detect and prevent fraudulent transactions;

(c)         analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our website;

(d)         where we buy or sell any businesses or assets, we may disclose your information to the prospective buyer or seller (or their advisers) or if part or all of our assets or business    are acquired by a third party, our customer data will be one of the assets transferred;

(e)         if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our **Terms of Use** and other agreements; and

(f)         to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

Additionally, where you have consented to receive cookies, we allow third parties such as Google and Doubleclick by Google to place cookies on your device in order to show you online advertising on other (non-viagogo) websites that you visit. Google will collect information about you (such as pages you have viewed and events you may be interested in) in order to select and serve relevant adverts to you. Further information about Google’s and Doubleclick’s use of cookies to deliver advertising content can be found on Google’s website [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl=en), and to opt-out of Google’s and Doubleclick’s use of cookies, you can control your Google advertising settings [here.](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) __

For information about our use of cookies (including by Google and Doubleclick) and how to decline them or turn them off please read our **Cookies Policy**.

**_Ensuring that use of your information is lawful_**

We take appropriate measures to ensure that all processing of your personal information by us, or by our service providers, is lawful.  The lawful basis for the processing of your personal information will depend on the purposes for which we process your information.

Much of the personal information we collect from you is necessary for us to provide our services to you in line with our **Terms of Use**. This includes most of the information you provide to us when setting up a customer account and making transactions via our website or app.

Some of the processing we conduct is necessary in pursuit of our legitimate interests in developing our website and apps and ensuring that they deliver relevant and focused content to you. We may profile your information, including by combining information we collect from you about your use of the website and apps with other information we hold about you, to help us to achieve these outcomes.

We require your consent to process information we process for marketing purposes and to maintain your customer account with us. You don’t have to provide your consent, and can withdraw it at any time. However, if you do not provide us with consent to maintain a customer account, your account on our website and access to the associated services will be suspended or terminated. There are no consequences of withdrawing your consent for marketing purposes.

Finally, sometimes we also need to process your personal information to comply with our legal obligations. This includes in relation to fraud prevention, sanctions screening checks, complaints and investigations or litigation.

For information about your rights, see **_Your Privacy rights_** (which forms part of this Privacy Notice).

**_Where do we send your information?_**

We may transfer your personal information outside of the European Economic Area (EEA) to other companies within our group, and to sellers and external suppliers based outside of the EEA.

When transferring your personal information outside of the EEA, we will (and will ensure that service providers acting on our behalf agree to) protect it from improper use or disclosure and ensure the same levels of protection are in place as are applied within the EEA.

We take the security of your personal data seriously. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access, loss or damage.

**_How long do we keep your information?_**

How long we keep your information will depend on the purpose for which we use it. While you are a customer of ours, we will only retain your information for as long as is necessary for those purposes.

If your account is terminated (by you or us), we will keep your information for a period of up to 7 years after termination (unless a longer period is prescribed by law) for the purposes of responding to legal disputes and legal or regulatory enquiries or investigations.

During and after expiry of this period, we will continue to use data which does not identify individual users in an aggregated form.  We use this aggregated data for data analysis, trend identification and research purposes, for example to gain insights about our users and to make improvements to our website.

**_Making a complaint_**

If you are not satisfied with how we’ve handled your information, please contact VGL Support Services Ireland Limited via [privacyrequest@orders.viagogo.com](mailto:privacyrequest@orders.viagogo.com).

If you are not satisfied with our response to your complaint or believe our processing of your information does not comply with data protection law, you can make a complaint to the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner at Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, Co. Laois R32 AP23, Ireland.  Tel: +353 (0761) 104 800 or on its website at [www.dataprotection.ie](https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/ZwnICXLAyhLwnPuMCf2d).   

**_Your Privacy rights_**

This section explains your rights in relation to your personal information in more detail. The various rights are not absolute and are subject to certain exceptions or qualifications.

We will respond to your requests in respect of your personal information free of charge (except in the following circumstances, where we may charge a reasonable fee to cover our administrative costs or may be entitled to refuse to respond:

  * manifestly unfounded or excessive/repeated requests, or
  * further copies of the same information).

Please consider your request responsibly before submitting it. We’ll respond as soon as we can. Generally, this will be within one month from when we receive your request but, if the request is going to take longer to deal with, we’ll let you know.

In order to exercise any of the rights described below, please contact us at VGL Support Services Ireland Limited via [privacyrequest@orders.viagogo.com](mailto:privacyrequest@orders.viagogo.com).

Further information and advice about your rights can be obtained from the Data Protection Commissioner using the contact details in the ‘ ** _Making a complaint_**’ Section above.

**_Accessing your information_**

**_Correcting your information_**

**_Erasing your information_**

**_Restricting processing of your information_**

**_Taking your personal data with you_**

**_Objecting to processing_**

**_Automated decision making and profiling_**

**_Accessing your information_**

**What can you request access to?**

You have the right to:

  * receive confirmation from us that your personal information is being processed;
  * access to your personal information; and
  * certain other details in relation to how we use your personal information (which is generally included in our Privacy Notice anyway).

You can request copies of paper and electronic records (including recorded calls, where applicable) about you that we hold, share or use. To deal with your request, we can ask for proof of your identity and enough personal information about you to enable us to locate the personal information you have requested.

**When will access not be provided?**

We can only provide you with _your personal information_ , not personal information about another person.  Also, where access would negatively affect another person’s rights, we’re not required to provide this.  Due to legal privilege, we may not be able to show you anything that we learned in connection with a claim or legal proceeding.

When requesting access to your personal information, to help us respond to your request quickly, please clearly set out in your request the personal information that you would like.  If this is not clear, we may need to ask for further information from you by way of clarification.

**_Correcting your information_**

You have the right to require us to correct inaccurate personal information that we hold about you.

If you tell us that the personal information we hold on you is incorrect, we will review it and if we agree with you, we will correct our records.  If we do not agree with you, we will let you know.  If you believe the records we hold on you are still incorrect, you can let us know in writing, and we will include your statement when we give your personal information to any third parties. 

If you believe that we hold incomplete personal information about you, you may also have the right to have the information completed, including by providing a supplementary statement.  Whether or not this right applies will depend on the purposes for which your personal information is being processed.

We need to notify any third parties with whom we have shared your personal information that you have made a correction request (see **_Who do we share your information with?_**).  We will take reasonable steps to do this, but if it is not possible or costly we may not be able to do so.

**How You Can See and Correct Your Information**

Generally, if you ask us in writing, we will let you see the personal information that we hold about you, and/or take steps to correct any inaccurate information.

Due to legal privilege, we may not be able to show you anything that we learned in connection with a claim or legal proceeding.

**_Erasing your information_**

**When can you request deletion of your personal information?**

Subject to the section below **_When can we refuse erasure requests?_**, you have a right to have your personal information erased, and to prevent further processing of your personal information, where:

  * the personal information is no longer necessary for the purpose it was originally collected/processed,
  * you withdraw your consent (where consent was previously provided and required for us to process the information),
  * you object to the processing, as long as our legitimate interests in processing your personal information don’t take priority over your objection,
  * we’ve been processing your personal information unlawfully, or
  * your personal information has to be erased in order to comply with a legal obligation.

**When can we refuse erasure requests?**

The right to erasure does not apply where your information is processed for certain specified reasons, including to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.

More importantly, if we have to erase your data we will not be able to continue to provide you with our services, so please carefully consider any request to erase your personal information. 

**Do we have to tell other recipients of your personal data about your erasure request?**

If you request that your personal information is deleted, and we have provided that information to any third parties (see **_Who do we share your information with?_**), we need to inform them about your erasure request, so they can also erase the personal information in question.  We will take reasonable steps to do this, but it may not always be possible.

Third parties can also refuse erasure requests if one of the exemptions above applies (for example where third parties need your information to establish, exercise or defend legal claims).

**_Restricting processing of your information_**

**When is restriction available?**

You have the right to restrict the processing of your personal information:

  * where you consider the information we hold to be inaccurate, in which case we have to restrict any processing while we verify the accuracy of your personal information,
  * when the processing we are carrying out is unlawful and you request us to restrict processing, rather than erasing your personal information,
  * if we no longer need the personal information, but you need it to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim, or
  * while we are considering our legitimate interests for processing your personal information to which you have objected in the circumstances detailed in paragraph (a) of **_Objecting to processing_**.

**What happens while processing is restricted?**

We can store your personal information, but we cannot carry out any further processing of it without your consent (unless processing is required in connection with legal claims, to protect another person’s rights or on important public interest grounds).

**Do we have to tell other recipients of your personal data about the restriction?**

Where we have disclosed your relevant personal information to third parties, we need to inform them about the restriction on the processing of your information, so that they do not continue to process it. 

We’ll take reasonable steps to do this, but it may not always be possible.

We will also let you know if we decide to lift a restriction on processing.

**_Taking your personal data with you_**

**When does the right to data portability apply?**

The right to data portability only applies:

  * to personal data you’ve provided to us (i.e. not any other information),
  * where we are processing your personal information because you have provided your consent for us to do so, or under a contract with you; and
  * when processing is carried out by automated means.

**When can we refuse requests for data portability?**

We can refuse your data portability request if the processing does not satisfy the above criteria.  Also, if the personal information concerns more than one individual, we may not be able to transfer the information to you if doing so would prejudice the other person’s rights.

**_Objecting to processing_**

You can object to processing in the following circumstances:

(a)   _Legitimate interests_

You have the right to object at any time to processing of personal information concerning you which is carried out because of our legitimate interests.

If we can show compelling legitimate grounds for processing your personal information which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or we need your personal information to establish, exercise or defend legal claims, we can continue to process it.  Processing of your personal information will be restricted while we make this assessment (see **_Restricting processing of your information_**). Otherwise, we must stop using the relevant personal information.

(b)   _Direct marketing_

You can object at any time to your personal information being used for direct marketing purposes (including profiling related to such direct marketing).

If you sign up to receive email marketing from us, you can opt-out at any time free of charge by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the message.  You may also choose to opt-out from receiving marketing materials from us at any time by updating your account settings or contacting us using the details in our Privacy Notice under the section headed **_Marketing_**

**_Automated decision making and profiling_**

You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which has legal consequences for you or which significantly affects you.

As explained in the main part of our Privacy Notice, we use technology that does make automatic decisions about transactions you are attempting to enter into (see **_How do we use your information?_**).

While we’re confident that the technology works, if you have any questions about our automated decision making process, you can contact us via [privacyrequest@orders.viagogo.com](mailto:privacyrequest@orders.viagogo.com%3C/a). Note: we won't respond to emails sent to this email address that are not related to your privacy rights. For other enquiries, please contact customer services  here .
